maven.co 2016-08-20

# Privacy Policy | Maven

This privacy policy, effective as of 12:01am EDT on June 8, 2016 applies to [**www.maven.co**](http://www.maven.co/) owned and operated by Maven Research, Inc. (“Maven”). This privacy policy describes how Maven Research, Inc. collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site: [**www.maven.co**](http://www.maven.co/).  It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

You agree that by visiting or using the www.maven.co website, or by becoming a user of Maven, that you are expressly and affirmatively consenting to Maven’s use and disclosure of the information that you provide as described below in this Privacy Policy. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time.

Maven Research, Inc. has received TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software or through aspects our platform other than this Web site. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [**www.maven.co**](http://www.maven.co/).

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe [**here**](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request "TRUSTe") .

## Your Personal Information

We collect information that you knowingly choose to disclose to us, including your first and last name, email, physical address, resume, employment status, disciplinary history, employment history and professional biography. We collect usage information as you interact with our website. We also collect additional information from our users concerning their interactions with each other.

We will use this information to:

  * Verify your identity and/or experience, decide whether to accept you as a user, process your registration, and manage our business relationship with you.
  * Enable your access to and use of our services.
  * Publish information about you on the website.
  * Supply you services or products that you purchase.
  * Collect payments from you or pay you for services you render.
  * Send you marketing communications.
  * Administer our internal business records.
  * Do generalized market research and statistical analysis.

We will not sell or share your personal information to anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts or similar technologies are used by Maven and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to customize your experience on this site. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [**here**](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)  (or if located in the European Union click [**here**](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

## Widgets

Our Web site may include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Single Sign-On

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as LinkedIn or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form.  Services like LinkedIn give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

## Blogs

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. If you cannot otherwise remove your information by using the tools available on our website, you can request the removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, by contacting us [here](https://help.maven.co/hc/en-us/requests/new). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Private and Public Status of Your Profile

The profile you create on our site will generally not be publically accessible, but Maven customers will be able to view limited personal information (such as your professional biography) when deciding whether to consult with you.  You may change the privacy settings of your profile through your account portal; in doing so, you may enable other Maven users to view your name and other personal information as you prefer.

## Communications You May Receive from Maven

### Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also send you any invitations for telephone consultations, survey participation, or similar opportunities to participate in Maven interactions. We will send you any communications necessary to schedule or reschedule your participation in these services. We will periodically send you emails to inform you of improvements to our service or to advise you of other Maven news, such as feature roll-outs that may change the way you interact with our service. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email to the extent practicable.

We will also send you service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

### Newsletters

We may periodically publish newsletters, and we will use your name and email address to send the newsletters to you. On occasion, these newsletters may provide you with information regarding promotions or special products or services. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. See “Opting out of Certain Communications” below for more information.

### Opting Out of Certain Communications

You may also opt out of receiving certain email and other information from us by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each communication. Please be aware that unsubscribing from a particular type of Maven communication may not unsubscribe you from all Maven communications; alternatively, you can manage your communication preferences from within your account.  You may not opt-out of Customer Service communications, which are not promotional in nature; if you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to close your account.

## Invite and Earn

If you choose to use our Invite & Earn referral feature to invite a contact to join Maven, we will ask you for your contact’s name and/or email address. We store this information for the sole purpose of inviting your contact to join Maven, as described below, and to track the success of our Invite & Earn feature.

We utilize an Import Contacts feature to help you invite contacts to join Maven. Our Site is capable of importing from many different email address book platforms. On the Invite and Earn page, you may select from which email address book you would like to import your contacts to our site. You will then be prompted through a step-by-step process that will allow you to import names and email addresses from your email address book. Once your contacts are successfully imported, you may select or deselect any or all of them to choose whom you wish to invite, and then click “Invite” to send them an invitation.

Each person that you invite will receive three email invitations to join Maven. The first invitation will be sent immediately when you click “Invite”. If the invitee does not respond, a reminder invitation will be sent three days later, and a final reminder invitation will be sent one week after the first reminder. Invitations may indicate that they were sent by you. All invitations contain unsubscribe links through which the invitee may decline the invitation.

## Our Security Procedures

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information you submit to us, both during transmission and once we receive and store it, whether you submit it to us online through the website or offline through other communication. Your account information is located on a secured server behind a firewall. We may collect the following sensitive information to facilitate payments from users to us, or to facilitate our transfer of payments to users: bank account (ACH) and/or wire transfer information and PayPal account information. When you enter sensitive information on our site, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). However, you should understand that no method of transmission of information over the Internet, or any particular method of electronic storage of that information, is absolutely secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

For Non-United States residents: By using our website and our service, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States. The United States does not have federal data protection laws of the same standard as certain other jurisdictions, such as the European Union. We will make reasonable efforts to keep your personal information secure at all times. Your personal information will be stored on a secure database in the United States which will be accessed only by authorized persons.

## When We Will Disclose Your Personal Information

We will disclose your personal information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity, or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (i) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (ii) protect our rights or property or the rights and property of our affiliated companies; (iii) prevent a crime or protect United States national security; or (iv) protect the personal safety of users or the public.

From time to time, and subject to applicable laws, we may also share your information with third-party vendors who will be authorized to use this information solely to perform services for us (such as an ASP hosting services, online identity verification services, payment processing services, marketing services, etc.) We will ensure that any such contractors, agents, vendors, partners or licensees that we hire or enter into transactions with apply an equivalent degree of security and confidentiality regarding your personal information as we do.

We may disclose and transfer information to a third party who acquires all or a substantial portion of our business. In addition, in the event we become the subject of a bankruptcy proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, we or our trustee in bankruptcy, may sell, license or otherwise dispose of your personal information in a transaction approved by the bankruptcy court.

## Links to Other Sites

This website may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave our website and to read the privacy statements of such other websites that you travel to.

## Access to and Modification of Your Information

You may review, correct, update, delete inaccuracies or change your account information at any time. To change your account information, simply log into your account, go to your Maven Profile, review your account information and, if you wish, edit it with the options provided, which edits will be updated when you save them to the site.

## Closing Your Account

You can [close your account](https://app.maven.co/maven/current/profile/account) with us at any time, in which event we will remove your profile from our profile database. Information that you remove in this manner may persist in backup or cached copies for a reasonable period of time, or as deemed legally prudent or required, but will not be generally available to any user of our website.

## Age Restriction

Our website and services are not intended for anyone under 18 years of age. We do not knowingly collect or store personal information from people under 18 years of age.

## Future Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to materially change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on our website prior to the changes becoming effective so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we may disclose it.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or any of our privacy practices please [contact us here](https://help.maven.co/hc/en-us/requests/new).

3661 Buchanan Street  
Suite 400  
San Francisco, CA 94123

_**Rev. June 8, 2016**_
